TOMÁŠ PILAŘ

21 St Bartholomew's Court \diamond Cambridge, CB5 8JB, United Kingdom $+44 \cdot 7531 \cdot 784896 \diamond$ sir.integra@gmail.com

A friendly, competent and dedicated software engineer with experience in UEFI and Linux kernel drivers. Prefers to work with a good team, designing and delivering well crafted products. Spare time is filled with friends playing board games or live-action games, or learning more about the technologies he works with.

- "Rare Depictions of Homo Programmeris Systemus"

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Xilinx Inc.
Staff Software Engineer

· UEFI Technical Lead and Linux Driver Developer

- · Full ownership of the UEFI Project including design, development, test and CI
- · Mentored junior member of the UEFI team

Solarflare Communications

June 2017 - July 2019 Cambridge, UK

July 2019 - Present

Cambridge, UK

Senior Software Engineer

- · UEFI Driver and Linux Driver Developer
- · Developed industry contacts facilitating higher quality of the UEFI products in-house.
- · Tutored junior members of other teams to disseminate institutional knowledge
- \cdot Collaborated cross-team to design specifications, implement features, develop OEM products, and debug complex issues.

Solarflare Communications

June 2014 - June 2017 Cambridge, UK

 $Software\ Engineer$

- · Test Automation Engineer and Test Developer, Linux Driver Developer
- · Designed and implemented test cases for multiple products using asynchronous Python framework based on twisted
- · Pioneered in-house CI frameworks streamlining the development process
- · Thoroughly benchmarked the linux kernel driver using a custom-built tool
- · Created in-house test harness for product web-UI using the Selenium framework

EDUCATION

University of Warwick, UK

October 2010 - June 2014

PhD in Particle Physics

Thesis on analysing data from LHCb to extract Standard Model parameters

Transferrable Doctoral Skills Course

Long Term Attachment in CERN, Geneva (14 months)

University of Warwick, UK

October 2006 - June 2010

MMathPhys (2.1), Thesis in Particle Physics

BASG Milana Hodžu, Sučany, Slovak Republic

October 2001 - June 2006

A-level equivalent (AAAABB)

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Systems Programming (Linux & UEFI) C (5 years)

Test Development and Automation Python (7 years), Jenkins (2 years)

Version Control Git and Mercurial (5 years)

Data Analysis C++ and ROOT (2 years)

Database Design & Administration

T-SQL, mySQL, mariaDB

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

GAUSS Monte Carlo Simulation Group

Decay Files repository manager

EvtGen Development Group

Development and technical support

LHCb UK Student Group

Convener

University of Warwick Computing Society

Co-President

Warwick Conferences

Lead Conference Assistant

October 2011 - June 2014

LHCb Collaboration, CERN

October 2010 - June 2014

University of Warwick, UK

June 2012 - December 2012

LHCb Collaboration, CERN

February 2007 - January 2009

University of Warwick, UK

June 2008 - September 2009

Warwick Conferences, Coventry

OTHER SKILLS

Languages Slovak & Czech (Native), English (Bilingual), French (Intermediate)

Management Software

Methodology **Public Speaking** JIRA, Bugzilla, Reviewboard, Slack Agile development and Continuous Integration

Experience chairing meetings (up to ~ 40 people)

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

Professional

Low-level programming (system software or firmware), solving complex problems

Designing robust systems that last, leaving code in better shape, bringing hardware to life

Imparting institutional knowledge

Personal

Games (board, computer, card, and live action), literature, theatre, musicals, travelling, swing dancing

COMMUNICATIONS

UEFI Plugfest Autumn 2016 - Current

Regular attendee on behalf of Solarflare Communications

Charm mixing in $D^0 \to K_S \pi \pi$ at LHCb

https://cds.cern.ch/record/2008671?ln=en

June 2014

University of Warwick

Model-independent measurement of mixing parameters in $D^0 \to K_S \pi \pi$ decays

http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2FJHEP04%282016%29033

April 2016 Journal of High Energy Physics

Charm mixing and CP violation at LHCb

May 2013

Large Hadron Collider Physics Conference

Barcelona, Spain

Measuring charm mixing using a model-independent technique in $D^0 \to K_S hh$

Institute of Physics HEP Conference

Liverpool, UK

April 2013

REFERENCES

Dinan Gunawardena Director, Xilinx Inc.

2017 - Current

+44 7808 926449, dinan@ieee.com

Robert Stonehouse

June 2014 - June 2019

Linux Driver Team Lead, Solarflare Communications

+44 7815 068929, rstonehouse@gmail.com